- In this video, you will learn
about I/O Redirection and Piping.
So, let's start with redirection.
Redirection is used to manipulate
input and output of commands.
And there are three ways of doing it:
standard input, also known as the zero.
The zero is for the file descriptor,
and the file descriptor is
something used internally
by the Linux kernel to
take care of redirection.
And the zero is always
your standard input.
And the standard input normally represents
your keyboard attached to your computer.
And if you want to get
information from somewhere else,
well, there is a smaller than redirector.
Now, the thing with the
smaller than redirector
is that you don't need it that often,
because many commands don't
need a smaller than redirector
to take their input from
a file for instance,
but this would give you something
sort smaller than etc services.
And I can only say, if you would tell me,
Hey we can do that without a smaller than.
And I would say, yeah, you are right.
But standard input redirectors
are just not used that often.
That's not the case for
standard output redirector.
The standard output redirector,
normally your standard output.
That's your screen, your terminal
attached to your computer
and results of commands
are sent to your computer.
And you can redirect it
using a greater than sign.
So if you use ls greater then to ~ myfile
then it'll create myfile
in your home directory.
Do notice that a single greater than sign
will override destination
if it already exists.
if you don't want to override but append
then you use a double redirect.
That will add it to the end of the file.
Also convenient is the option
to redirect standard error.
We have seen that on a
couple of occasions already.
In order to redirect standard
error, you use 2 greater than
in which the 2 is the file descriptor 2
and the greater than will send it
wherever you want to send it.
Like right here, for
instance, where we use
2 greater than dev null. dev
null is a discard device.
Anything you send to the dev
null device will be discarded.
You won't see it anymore.
And this is a perfect
way to make sure that you
don't see any error messages
while running commands.
And here we have another example
which is using ampersand greater than.
Now what is ampersand greater than?
That will represent the standard output
as well as the standard error.
Now that is stuff that you
normally don't want to write
to the dev null device, but you might want
to capture all that
information in a specific file.
And then this is how you
do it. Before we move over
and talk about piping, let's
go check out these examples.
So, right. Let me start using
sort smaller than etc services
to use etc services as the
thing that we want sort.
And yeah, the smaller than
is just redirecting the
the input from the
keyboards to etc services.
Right. As I was telling you before
that's not a very
convincing example, I know.
But ls greater than, lsfile
is a more convincing example.
What do we get? We get
no output on screen.
We get output in lsfile.
Which is the list of files just generated.
Now, if I use who greater than to lsfile
then I'm doing an, a standard
output redirection again.
And after checking the contents of lsfile
you have seen that who
command has overwritten.
And if you don't want
to override but append
then you should use a double redirect.
The double redirect, as you
can see is adding the output
of the command to the
file we just created.
Now, how about the error messages?
Well, let me do grab a root on etc start.
That's an example that we've seen before.
Many, many permission
denied is a directory
which are error messages.
And if you don't care
about the error messages.
2 greater than dev null.
And that will make sure that you only see
the regular output. Now, what is happening
if you make that ampersand greater than.
Ampersand greater than dev null
is showing nothing at
all. That might be useful
for processes that are
supposed to be running
in the background
but not for interactive
commands, like grep.
So let me create outfile and
write the output to outfile.
And there we can see the, the output
including the error messages.
We have the file descriptor 1 as well as
as the file descriptor 2
both being sent to outfile.
Let's go check out piping.
So a pipe is used to send
the output of one command
to be used as input for a second command.
This also is something that we have
already seen a couple of times.
Like ps aux, grab http. Where ps aux is
showing a lot of running
processes and grep http is
filtering out the lines
that contain the text http.
In combination with the pipe,
you might see the tee command.
Now, what is the tee command?
The tee command combines
redirection and piping.
It allows you to write
the output to somewhere
and at the same time, use it
as input for another command
like ps aux, tee psfile, pipe grep ssh.
Let me show you these examples.
So to start with ps aux, ps aux.
Which by the way, is
another BSD style commands.
This command is showing a list
of all the processes currently running.
And if you want to verify whether
or not SSH is running well,
this is what you can do.
This is an ordinary pipe
as we have already seen.
Now, how does that work with, with tee?
Well, I am going to pipe to tee.
psfile or whatever you wanna call it.
And then I'm going to pipe to grep SSH.
Here we can see the
result of the grep SSH,
but at the same time,
it has created psfile.
So in psfile, we have the ps aux
and the grep SSH is working on the ps aux.
The tee is really like
the uppercase letter T.
It's sending you two different directions
to a file as well as to the pipe
where it is further treated by grep SSH.
This tee can be handy
if you want to have an
additional opportunity to
analyze what exactly was happening
before you applied the
command after the pipe.
And that's all, let's continue.